Johan Sebastian Medina Castaño

Front-end Developer & Web Engineer

jsebastianm1113@gmail.com +573165325256 https://www.linkedin.com/in/johan-medina-jsmc/

Career summary

I am an Interaction Designer dedicated to Front-end development with over 5 years of experience in international markets focusing on develop digital products with design criteria for brands like Updater (leader in moving services based in USA), Egon Zehnder (enhancer of leadership services operating in 36 countries), and more industries. I always keep on track of new technologies to generate immersive interactions, following up quality assurance and testing environments, business and requirement analysis, and fluent communication both written and spoken in English and Spanish. I feel passionate to be at the forefront of new incoming technologies and methodologies to empower new business opportunities and impacting users life.

Professional experience

MONSTARLAB New York, USA

Web Engineer

February 2021 - Nowadays · 3 years

Developed web applications with React for brands like Updater, Egon Zehnder, StoreEase and Treasury mainly located in USA and international markets. I defined structure for projects following up server side rendering standards with Next JS and components pattern with React; preparing documentation with JSDoc, Unit Testing, Storybook and documents placed in code and Notion. I follow up communication with clients to implement new technologies like three is and react-three-fiber, and new upcoming tools like Artificial Intelligence for coding processes and explorational projects for Monstarlab.

- Successfully launched to production 5 web products with React technologies and web services including payment process, data analysis, testing and documentation for following updates.
- Implemented new APIs, Re-branding updates, new Services and Payment flows in a period of 1 year to help updater to automate 25% of all US household moves with the largest brands in real estate (half of NMHC's top 50).
- Developed and launched from 0 in a period of 1 year, an LAS platform with React technologies for Egon Zehnder to operate in more of 30 countries around the world, automating leadership management processes in companies.
- Implemented new services and payment flows in a React web app of renting storage, helping StoreEase to automate its connection with VCS and Smart Units reaching out facilities placed in 15 states of USA.

WE ARE ANGULAR Cali, Colombia

React Developer & UX / UI Designer

August 2019 - January 2021 · 2 years & 5 months

In charge of lead conversations with clients to define POC's and technologies to implement. Led front-end development implementations with React technologies following server side rendering standards with Next.js, components pattern, and unit testing; and led implementations with wordpress. Designed web pages in figma with high fidelity of branding applications and interactions with the end user of the product.

- Advised and launched digital products as web pages and web applications for 6 local brands to begin in the digital in the market.
- Advised, ideate and launched successfully a web application as multiplayer videogame with pixel art, to adapt courses of Icesi university in times of covid for daily usage of more of 100 students per semester.

Education

ICESI UNIVERSITY

Santiago de Cali, Colombia September 2015 - January 2021

BE Interactive Media Design, Cum Laude

Part of the Interactive Media Design student group as Design and Communication Director and as Consultant.

Languages

SPANISH

Native

ENGLISH

C1, Written and Spoken

Conference

3D ON THE WEB - A PERFORMANCE CHALLENGE

Borderless Engineering Conference

September 26 of 2022

Borderless Engineering

Developed with react three fiber all 3D environments and scenes showed in the conference.

https://www.borderlessengineeringconf.com

https://youtu.be/iStx3AyashE?si=bO4zYHFEvelRZK81

Skills & Interest

DEVELOPMENT

React, Javascript, Typescript, Next.js, Node.js, Git, Github, Three.js, SCSS, Styled Components, Storybook, JSDoc, Jest, React Three Fiber, Redux, Ai tools, CSS & HTML, Firebase, Mongo DB, Docker, Wordpress

MANAGEMENT

Client relationship, POC, Scrum methodologies, Requirements identification, Jira, Asana, Miro, Confluence

DESIGN

Information architecture, Human-Computer Interaction, Product testing, UX & UI design

INTERESTS

Front-end development, Metaverse, VR/AR/MR, 3D environments, Immersive tools, Interactive installations, Creative technology, Data visualization